mooc.org 2016-03-11

# mooc.org - Privacy Policy

**MOOC.org Privacy Policy**  
Effective date: September 10, 2013 

### Confidentiality & security of personal information

We care about the confidentiality and security of your personal information. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to keep your Personal Information (as defined below) secure. However, no method of transmitting or storing electronic data is ever completely secure, and we therefore cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted to or stored by the MOOC.org website (the “Site,” which consists of all content and pages located within the MOOC.org web domain). As used in this Privacy Policy, “edX,” “we,” “us” and “our” refer to edX Inc., the owner of the Site.

This Privacy Policy only applies to information that we collect through the Site and does not apply to information that we may collect from you in other ways (for example, this policy does not apply to information that you may provide to us over the phone, by fax or through conventional mail).

### What you consent to by using our site

By accessing, browsing, submitting information to, or registering for the Site, you consent and agree that information about you collected on or through the Site may be used and disclosed in accordance with the Privacy Policy and the Terms of Service (as may be amended from time to time), and as permitted or required by law, and that such information may be transferred to, processed in and stored in the United States and elsewhere. If you do not agree with these terms, then please do not access, browse, submit information to, or register for the Site. As used in this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means any information about yourself that you may provide to us when using the Site which may include (but is not limited to) your name, contact information, gender, date of birth, and occupation.

### Information we collect and how we use it

We collect information, including Personal Information, when you provide that information to us via the Site. In addition, we track information indicating, among other things, which pages of the Site were visited, the order in which they were visited, when they were visited and which hyperlinks and other user interface controls were used.

We also may log the IP address, operating system and browser software used by each user of the Site, and we may be able to determine from an IP address a user’s Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. Various web analytics tools are used to collect this information. Some of the information is collected through cookies (small text files placed on your computer that store information about you, which can be accessed by the Site). You should be able to control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your web browser. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the “Help” section of the toolbar. If you reject our cookies, many functions and conveniences of this Site may not work properly.

Among other things, we may use the information about you collected on or through the Site (including your Personal Information) in connection with the following: 

  * To monitor and detect violations of the Terms of Service, as well as other misuses and potential misuses of the Site.
  * To archive this information and/or use it for future communications with you.
  * To maintain and improve the functioning and security of the Site and our software, systems and network.
  * As otherwise described to you at the point of collection, pursuant to your consent, or as otherwise permitted by law.

### Sharing with Third Parties

We may share this information (including Personal Information) with third parties as follows: 

  * To respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or another government agency; to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, security or technical issues, or to enforce any applicable Terms of Service, Honor Code or this Privacy Policy; as otherwise may be required by applicable law; or to protect our rights, property or safety or those of others. 
  * With affiliates of edX or the other institutions, businesses or entities that provide courses through the Site, or with any successors of edX or such institutions, businesses or entities in the event of a merger, acquisition or reorganization, for their use consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * As otherwise described to you at the point of collection, pursuant to your consent, or otherwise as permitted by law.

In addition, we may share aggregated information that does not personally identify you with the public and with third parties, including, e.g., researchers, the media and business partners. 

### Links to Other Websites

The Site may contain links to websites published by other content providers. These other websites are not under our control, and you acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by such websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of each website you visit and use.

### Changing our privacy policy

Please note that we review and may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting on this page, with an updated effective date. By accessing the Site after any changes have been made, you signify your agreement on a prospective basis to the modified Privacy Policy and any changes contained therein. Be sure to return to this page periodically to ensure familiarity with the most current version of this Privacy Policy.

### Privacy concerns

If you have privacy concerns, have disclosed data you would prefer to keep private, or would like to access the information we maintain about you, please contact us at privacy@edx.org.

### Sign Up for Updates

mooc.org goes live in the first half of 2014. Are you interested in creating or hosting courses on mooc.org? Complete one of the three forms below and let us know how mooc.org fits into your plans. We'll be in touch as we get closer to launch. 

### More Information

  * #### Read the full press release

EdX Announces Partnership with Google to Expand Open Source Platform. Google will collaborate with edX on mooc.org, new destination and hosting site for online learning... Read More

  * #### [What is Open edX?](http://code.edx.org/)

Open edX is the open-source educational platform developed by edX and its open source partners, including leading institutions. It powers the edX.org destination site and research initiatives and will power mooc.org. [Learn More](http://code.edx.org/)

* * *

  * EdX is a not-for-profit enterprise composed of 30 leading global institutions, the xConsortium, focused on transforming online and on-campus learning on an open source platform. Mooc.org, is a new site for non-xConsortium universities, institutions, businesses, governments and teachers to build and host their courses for a global audience. This site will be powered by the Open edX platform.
